Still got it.
[SHOTGUN PLAYING ON RADIO]
[广播中传来枪声]
[SINGING] I said, Shotgun
Shoot 'em for he runs now
Do the jerk, baby
Do the jerk now
Hey
Put on your red dress
And then you go downtown now
I said buy yourself a shotgun now
We're gonna break it down baby now
We're gonna load it up baby now
And then you shoot him 'fore he runs now
I said, Shotgun
Shoot 'em 'fore he runs now
Do the jerk baby
Do the jerk now
Hey
Put on your high-heeled shoes
I said we're goin' down here Listen to 'em play the blues
We're gonna dig potatoes
We're gonna pick tomatoes
I said, Shotgun
Shoot 'em 'fore he runs now
Do the jerk baby
Do the jerk now
Hey
I said it's Twine Time
那是什么?
What's that?
一个老朋友
An old friend.
我在翻衣柜时发现它静静的躺在那儿
I was rummaging through a closet and it was just sitting there.
它看上去不错　保罗　很有性格
It's nice, Paul. It's got character.
当我完成自己的第一部作品时　我就是夹着它四处寻找出版商
When I wrote my first book, I used to carry it around in this while I was looking for a publisher.
那时我是个作家
I was a writer then.
你现在还是
You're still a writer.
但自从我写了米瑟瑞系列后就不是了
Haven't been a writer since I got in the Misery business.
那是个很不错的系列　它还会继续推出续集的
It's not a bad business. And it would still be growing, too.
这是初版的米瑟瑞的孩子
The first printing for Misery's Child
是最成功的　发行量超过100万册
was the most ever. Over a million.
马修，别再说下去了
Marcia, please.
米瑟瑞 查斯顿让你负担得起女儿看牙医的费用
Misery Chastain put braces on your daughter's teeth
还让她读完了大学
and is putting her through college,
让你买了两套房屋　并且让你每次听Knick的音乐会都能坐在楼上包厢里
bought you two houses and floor seats to the Knicks.
而你用什么再感谢她呢？你抛弃并杀害了她！
And what thanks does she get? You go and kill her!
我从没打算靠它生活
I never meant for it to become my life.
此外要是我现在不摆脱她
And if I hadn't gotten rid of her now,
我就会把她的故事继续没完没了的写下去
I'd have ended up writing her forever.
现在我得去科罗拉多州设法完成新书的写作了
Now I'm leaving for Colorado to try to finish the new book.
如果我能完成这部作品，我想自己墓碑上的碑文内容也就有了
If I can make this work, I might just have something I want on my tombstone.
我是你的头号书迷
I'm your number-one fan.
没什么可担心的
There's nothing to worry about.
你会没事的　我会好好照顾你的
You're gonna be just fine. I'll take good care of you.
我是你的头号书迷
I'm your number-one fan.
这是什么地方?
Where...
我们在银溪郡附近
We're just outside Silver Creek.
我待了多久了？
How long?
你睡了两天了　你会好起来的
You've been here two days. You're gonna be okay.
我叫安妮 威尔克斯
My name is Annie Wilkes.
我的头号书迷
My number-one fan.
是的　没错　我还是一名护士
Yes. That's right. I'm also a nurse.
来，把这些吃下去
Here, take these.
来吧
Here.
- 这是什么？　　- 这是Novril
- What are they?　　 - They're called Novril.
止疼用的
They're for your pain.
谢谢你
Thank you.
为什么我不是在医院里?
How come I'm not in a hospital?
暴风雪太厉害　我不能冒险把你送到那儿
The blizzard was too strong.I couldn't risk trying to get you there.
我打电话试过，但是电话线都断了
I tried calling, but the phone lines are down.
你不要再乱动了　你需要休息
You mustn't tire yourself. You've gotta rest.
你差点就没命了
You almost died.
张开嘴
Open wide.
你只要稍微动一下腿你就会叫得像是在唱歌剧一样，不是吗？
Your legs just sing grand opera when you move, don't they?
你的伤会好起来的，保罗，我向你保证
It's not gonna hurt forever, Paul, I promise you.
我还可以走路吗?
Will I be able to walk?
当然可以
Of course you will.
你的手臂也会没事的
And your arm will be fine, too.
之前你的肩膀严重脱臼
Your shoulder was pretty badly dislocated.
虽然有些不好处理，不过我最后还是“啪”的一下将它推回去了
It was a little stubborn, but I finally popped it back in.
让我最为感到骄傲的是治疗你的腿伤
What I'm most proud of is the work I did on those legs.
考虑到我家里条件有限
Considering what I had around the house,
不过我并不认为能有医生可以比我做得更好
I don't think there's a doctor who could've done any better.
其实没有看上去那么糟
It's not nearly as bad as it looks.
你双腿胫骨粉碎性骨折
You have a compound fracture of the tibia in both legs,
右腿腓骨也有骨折
and the fibula in the right leg is fractured, too.
我可以听到骨头在里边移动
I could hear the bones moving,
所以你的腿最好别动
so it's best for your legs to remain immobile.
只要道路交通恢复
And as soon as the roads open
我就把你送到医院去
I'll take you to a hospital.
目前，你需要长时间的静养
Meantime, you've got a lot of recovering to do,
我认为能在我家休养对我来说真是莫大的荣幸
and I consider it an honor that you'll do it in my home.
我是纽约市的马修 辛德尔
This is Marcia Sindell, I'm calling from New York City.
我想同银溪郡的警察局长或是警长通话
I'd like to speak to the Silver Creek Chief of Police or Sheriff.
你想他们中的哪一位通话呢?
Which one of them do you want?
谁有空就同谁吧
Whichever one's not busy.
好的，我非常确定他们两人现在都有空，辛德尔女士
Well, I'm pretty sure they're both not busy, Miss Sindell
因为这两个职位都由我一人兼任
since they're both me.
同时我还是警察福利协会的会长
I also happen to be president of the Policeman's Benefit Association,
巡警退休基金会的主席
chairman of the Patrolman's Retirement Fund,
要是你需要一位好的钓鱼指导，那情况会更糟
and if you need a good fishing guide, you could do a lot worse.
就叫我老兄吧　这里人人都这样叫我
Call me Buster. Everybody does.
有什么要帮忙的吗?
What can I do for you?
我是个出版经纪人，嗯我... 给你打电话让我感觉自己像在做件傻事
I'm a literary agent, and I... I feel like a fool calling you,
我认为我的一位客户　保罗 谢尔顿
but I think one of my clients, Paul Sheldon,
也许遭遇到什么不测了
might be in some kind of trouble.
你是说保罗 谢尔顿，那位作家?
You mean Paul Sheldon the writer?
他是你的客户，嗯?
He's your client, huh?
是的，没错
Yes, he is.
所有人都很喜欢他写的米瑟瑞小说
Everybody sure likes those Misery books.
我相信你知道保罗多年来都会到银溪旅馆
I'm sure you know that Paul's been coming to the Silver Creek Lodge
去完成作品的写作
for years to finish his books.
我知道他过去六个星期都在这里
I understand he's been up here the last six weeks.
嗯，别挂电话　我刚才给旅馆打过电话
Well, not quite. I just called there
他们说踏上周二就已经退房了
and they said he checked out last Tuesday.
这不是有些不对劲吗？
Isn't that a little strange?
我不知道　他通常都会给你电话的吗？
I don't know. Does he usually phone you
在他退房之前？
before he checks out of a hotel?
不，当然不会　只是他女儿一直都没有接到他的电话
No, of course not. It's just that his daughter hasn't heard from him,
每次他有新书著成的时候，他通常都会同她联系的
and when he has a new book coming out, he usually keeps in touch.
而现在他一点儿消息都没有，我…
Now when there wasn't any word from him, I...
你认为他很可能失踪了，嗯？
You think he might be missin', huh?
我本不想打这个电话的　告诉我我是不是有些多虑了
I hate that I made this call. Tell me I'm being silly.
也许是有点过分担心了， 不过让我告诉你接下来我将采取怎样的措施
A little overprotective, maybe, but tell you what I'll do.
虽然目前还没收到任何报告
Nothing's been reported out here,
但我会将他的名字加入我们的系统中，此外
but I'll put his name through our system, and
如有其他任何发现，我会给你回电话的
if anything turns up, I'll call you right back.
您能那样做我很感激　非常感谢
I'd appreciate that. Thanks a lot.
再见，辛德尔女士
Goodbye, Miss Sindell.
有人给我们打电话啊? 真是个忙碌的早晨
We got a phone call? Busy morning.
没错　除了工作就是，工作，工作
Yeah. Work, work, work.
维吉尼亚，上次暴风雪是什么时候的事儿？
Virginia, when was that blizzard?
上周二　怎么了?
Last Tuesday. Why?
没甚么
No reason.
我在想，你在暴风雪中找到我简直就是某种奇迹
I guess it was kind of a miracle, you finding me.
不，这根本不是什么奇迹
No, it wasn't a miracle at all.
不如说，我一直都在跟着你
In a way, I was following you.
你跟着我?
You were following me?
是啊，你住在银溪郡里对我来说没有任何秘密可言
Well, it wasn't any secret to me you were staying at the Silver Creek,
这就是头号书迷的区别
seeing as how I'm your number-one fan and all.
有时我会在夜里前往旅馆那儿，坐在外边
Some nights I'd just tool on down there and sit outside
抬头看着从你那间客房透出的灯光
and look up at the light in your cabin
于是我就试着想象这位世界上最伟大的作家正在那间屋子里做什么呢
and I'd try to imagine what was goin' on in the room of the world's greatest writer.
把最后那段话再说一遍好吗，我没听清楚
Say the last part again, I didn't hear you.
别动
Don't move now.
我可不想伤到你的脖子
I wouldn't want to hurt this neck.
是这样，那天下午我正好在回家的路上
Well, the other afternoon I was on my way home
看见你走出旅馆
and there you were, leavin' the lodge.
于是我就在想这位文学天才干嘛要在
And I wondered why a literary genius would go for a drive
暴风雪即将来临的时候开车外出？
when there was a big storm comin'.
我不知道会有暴风雪
I didn't know there was a big storm coming.
噢，那你真是幸运　同样的，我也很幸运
Well, lucky for you, I did. And lucky for me, too,
因为你还活着，这样就可以继续写出更多的书了
'cause now you're alive and you can write more books.
噢，保罗，我看过你的所有作品
Oh, Paul, I've read everything of yours.
米瑟瑞系列小说　我简直烂熟于心
The Misery novels. I know 'em all by heart.
一共8本　我都非常喜欢
All eight of 'em. I love them so.
噢，你真是太善良了
Well, you're very kind.
而且才华横溢
And you're very brilliant.
像个婴儿一样乖乖的　好了
Like a baby. All done.
谢谢
Thank you.
你认为电话线何时可以修复？我得同我的女儿通个电话
When do you think the phone lines'll be up? I have to call my daughter,
还有我想给我在纽约的经纪人打个电话
and I'd like to call my agent in New York
让她知道我还活着
and let her know I'm still breathing.
应该不用等太久了
It shouldn't be too much longer now.
一旦交通恢复，电话线很快就能修好
Once the roads are open, the phone lines'll be up in no time.
要是你把他们的电话号码给我，我会试着替你联系他们的
If you give me their numbers, I'll keep tryin' them for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
我可以向你提一个请求吗?
Could I ask you a favor?
我注意到在你的皮夹里有一部新的保罗 谢尔顿作品，因此
I noticed in your case there's a new Paul Sheldon book, and
我想否可以…
I wondered if maybe...
你想看它?
You want to read it?
嗯，如果您不介意的话
Well, if you wouldn't mind.
嗯，对于谁能在未出版前阅读我的手稿
Well, I do have a very hard-and-fast rule as to
我有非常严格的规定
who reads my stuff at this early stage.
只有我的编辑，我的经纪人
Only my editor, my agent,
以及在暴风雪中救我让我免于冻死在倾覆的车里的人才可以看
and anybody that saves me from freezing to death in a car wreck.
您永远想也象不到您给我的是怎样一种特殊的待遇
You'll never realize what a rare treat you've given me.
我的大男孩儿，你的疼痛就像时钟一样分秒不差
Boy, it's like clockwork the way your pain comes.
我给你拿Novril来，保罗
I'll get you your Novril, Paul.
请原谅我不停在说些废话让您感觉很无聊
Forgive me for prattling away and making you feel all oogy.
您这本新书叫什么名字？
What's your new book called?
我现在还没有想好
I don't have a title yet.
是写什么的?
What's it about?
我不知道
I don't know.
我知道这听起来有些不可思议，不过到目前为止我除了写米瑟瑞
I know it sounds crazy, but I haven't written anything
没写过关于别的书
but Misery for so long.
你为什么不看看，然后告诉我
Why don't you read it, and you can tell me
你认为它是写什么的？
what you think it's about?
说不定你能想出一个书名来
Maybe you can come up with a title.
听上去我好像能够办到！
Like I could do that!
银溪旅馆
谢尔顿先生离开时跟往常没有什么不同，老兄
There's nothin' unusual about Mr. Sheldon's leaving, Buster.
可从他点的香槟就能看出来
You can tell by the champagne.
也许你能，利比
Maybe you can, Libby.
不，要知道，在他准备离开前
No, see, he always orders a bottle of Dom Pérignon
他总会点上一瓶Dom Périgno香槟
when he's ready to go.
结账之后便走出大门
Then he pays up and he's out the door.
没有长途电话打来或是收到联邦快递包裹吗？
No long-distance phone calls or Federal Express packages?
有什么异常表现吗?
Anything out of the ordinary?
我不认为谢尔顿先生身上
I don't think Mr. Sheldon likes
有表现出什么异常的
for things to be out of the ordinary.
想想他是什么人吧，那么有名
Considering who he is and all, famous and all,
可从没有架子
he doesn't put on airs.
每次都开着同一辆65年款的野马汽车从纽约来
Drives up from New York in the same car each time, a '65 Mustang.
他说这有助于他进行思考
He says it helps him to think.
他还是个很好的住客
He's always been a good guest.
住在这里也非常的安静，连鬼魂都不会被打扰到
Never makes a noise, never bothers a soul.
我当然希望他不要发生什么事情
I sure hope nothing's happened to him.
我也是
So do I.
我打赌那辆旧野马车现在已经开进纽约了
I bet that old Mustang is pulling into New York right now.
我相信你说得没错　谢谢，利比
I'm sure you're right. Thanks, Libby.
不用客气
My pleasure.
我知道你的这本书自己只看了40页，不过...
I know I'm only 40 pages into your book, but...
不过什么?
But what?
没什么
Nothing.
它怎么样？
What is it?
噢，简直太荒谬了
Well, it's ridiculous.
我怎么有资格对您这样的人发表评论？
Who am I to make a criticism to someone like you?
没关系，我可以接受
It's all right, I can take it.
嗯，写得很精彩
Well, it's brilliantly written.
当然只要是您写的都非常精彩
But then everything you write is brilliant.
很粗俗吧?
Pretty rough so far?
里边那些咒骂的话，保罗
The swearing, Paul.
是的，我说过的
There, I said it.
那些…那些粗俗的字眼让你觉得很不舒服吗？
The... The profanity bothers you?
一点都不高贵
It has no nobility.
那些是贫民区的孩子们说的　我过去也生活在贫民区
These are slum kids.I was a slum kid.
那里每个人说话都是那样
Everybody talks like that.
他们才不是这样！（大妈把米瑟瑞代入自己身上了！）
They do not!
你认为当我到镇上的饲料店我会怎么说？
What do you think I say when I go to the feed store in town?
"瓦利，给我来袋他妈的猪食"
"Now, Wally, give me a bag of that F-ing pig feed
"还有10磅婊子养的牛饲料？"?
"and 10 pounds of that bitchly cow corn"?
要是在银行，我会这样跟博林杰夫人说
And in the bank, do I tell Mrs. Bollinger,
“给你他妈的混蛋支票
"Here's one big bastard of a check,
把神圣个你妈的钞票给我？“
"give me some of your Christing money"?
就是这样！你看看就是这样！看看你都让我做了些什么？
There! Look there! See what you made me do?
保罗 ，我很抱歉
Paul, I'm sorry.
我真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
有时我真的很激动　您能原谅我吗？
Sometimes I get so worked up. Can you ever forgive me?
没关系
It's fine.
我爱你，保罗
I love you, Paul.
我是指　你得思想　你的创造力
Your mind. Your creativity. That's all I meant.
嗯，这真的很刺激
Well, this sure is fun.
维吉尼亚，当你在这辆车上的时候
Virginia, when you're in this car
你不是我太太，而是我的副手
you're not my wife, you're my deputy.
噢，这位副手她宁愿呆在家里
Well, this deputy'd rather be home
同警长裹在一条被子里
under the covers with the sheriff.
- 停车　停车　　- 出什么状况了？出什么了？
- Stop. Stop　　- What? What?
看见这些折断的树枝没？
See that broken limb?
可能是被雪压断的
Could've been the weight of the snow.
是吗？可能是腐烂了，也可能是被风吹断了
Yeah? Could've been a rotten branch, could've been the wind,
还可能是别的很多事情
could've been a lot of things.
该死！
Damn!
需要帮忙吗？
Need some help?
不，我不过是自说自话！谢谢
No, I'm enjoyin' myself! Thank you.
你真的认为谢尔顿的车冲出了公路？
You really think Sheldon's out there?
我希望不是这样　如果是的话，他已经没命了
I hope not. If he is, he's dead.
我们去报社吧
Let's go to the newspaper office.
希望没吵醒你
I hope I didn't wake you.
没有，没关系
No, that's fine.
看看我都弄到了什么　商店里摆了你的书，保罗
Look what I got. They had it at the store, Paul.
商店里摆了好大一堆
There was a whole batch of 'em there
我一看见就马上掏出钱　我买到了第一本呃
and as soon as I saw it I slammed my money down. I got the first copy.
那么交通已经恢复了
Then the roads are open.
嗯，通向镇上的路通了，不过仅限于此
Well, the one to town is,but that's about it.
我给医院打过电话找首席外科医生谈过
I called the hospital and I talked to the head orthopedic surgeon
还告诉他您是谁以及事情的经过
and I told him who you were and what had happened.
他说只要没有感染你就不会有事
He said as long as there's no infection you're not in any danger,
一旦通向医院的道路恢复了
and as soon as the road to the hospital is open,
他们就会为你派辆救护车来
they'll send an ambulance for you.
电话能用了吗？
The phone's working?
噢，我的电话还没接通，不过镇上的已经恢复了
Well, mine's still out, but the ones in town were working just fine.
我已经跟你的经济人通过电话了
I called that agent of yours.
保罗，我刚看完书的前几页
Paul, I peeked at the very beginning.
第一页真是太棒了
What a wonderful first page.
一读到米瑟瑞 查斯顿这名字
Just to read the name Misery Chastain...
我女儿就会变得忘乎所以
My daughter's gotta be goin' nuts.
就像我最老，最亲密的朋友前来拜访一样
It's like a visit from my oldest, dearest friend.
我是说，我原本打算回家给她过生日的　今天是她生日
I mean, I'm supposed to be home for her birthday. It's today.
你的经纪人说她会告诉你女儿你没事
The agent said she would tell her you were okay,
不过我恐怕你只有等到明天了
but I'm afraid you'll have to wait till tomorrow
如果你打算亲自告诉她的话
if you want to talk to her yourself.
噢，保罗　你真是一位了不起的诗人
Oh, Paul. What a poet you are.
我给你做了我的拿手菜，威尔克斯炒蛋
I made you my specialty, scrambled eggs à la Wilkes.
现在我看到75页了
And I'm on Page 75.
我猜也就是说这本书还行吧
I guess that means it's okay.
不
No.
不，不是的，它…
No, it isn't, it's...
噢　我实在想不出用什么词来说好（其实我也想这么说）
Pooh. I can't think of any words.
说它”非常好“会是对你的侮辱吗？
Would "great" be insulting?
非常好我就已经很满意了
I can live with great.
不　它不只是非常好，它
No. It's not just great, it's
简直太完美了
perfect.
一部完美的，完美的作品
A perfect, perfect thing.
我想是时候让你们俩认识一下了
I thought it was time you two should meet.
保罗，跟我在这个世界上最喜爱的动物打个招呼吧
Paul, say hello to my favorite beast in the whole world,
这是我的米瑟瑞，它是头母猪
my sow Misery.
米瑟瑞?
Misery?
对　我跟你说过我是你的头号书迷
Yes. I told you I was your number-one fan.
对，我...我开始有些相信你了
Yeah, I'm... I'm starting to believe you.
这个农场从前很沉闷的
This farm was kind of dreary
只有几头母牛和鸡同我生活在一起
what with just a few cows and chickens and me.
但是自从有了米瑟瑞，一切都改变了（丰胸广告句式）
But when I got Misery here, everything changed.
她让我有了欢笑
She just makes me smile so.
她真的是一头很好的猪
She's a fine pig, is what she is.
我现在看到300页了，保罗，它简直用完美都不足以形容　是神圣
I'm on Page 300 now, Paul, and it's better than perfect. It's divine.
那个外国人在天花板上画的是什么？
What's the ceiling that dago painted?
是希斯廷教堂吗？
The Sistine Chapel?
对了！西斯廷教堂还有米瑟瑞的孩子
Yeah! That and Misery's Child.
是这个世界上仅有的两件神圣的事物！
Those are the only two divine things ever in this world!
当我丈夫离开我时，我丝毫没有准备
When my husband left me, I wasn't prepared.
那段日子很难熬
It wasn't an easy time.
有段时间我都感觉自己快要疯了
For a while I thought I might go crazy.
我知道那是怎样的一种感觉
I know how that can be.
我不知道你是怎样，不过我就是这样熬过去的
I don't know about you, but what I did to get through it
我全身心的投入工作
was I dove into work.
日以继夜
Days, nights.
在医院值夜班是孤独的
Night shifts can be lonely at a hospital.
于是我看了许多书
I did a lot of reading.
我就是在那时发现了米瑟瑞
That was when I first discovered Misery.
她让我感到开心　让我忘了我所有的烦恼
She made me so happy. She made me forget all my problems.
当然，我认为这其中也有些许是因为你的原因
Course, I suppose you had a little something to do with that, too.
是的，嗯…
Yeah, well...
我一页一页的不停的阅读着它们
I just kept reading them over and over.
当我只看了两章之后
I've only got two chapters to go on this one,
我就知道等我看完这遍之后我还会再一次从头看起
and I know when I finish I'll just turn right to the first page
然后再从头看一遍
and start reading it all over again.
我...
I'm...
- 尿完了?　　- 是的
- Done?　　- Yeah.
没问题
No problem.
谢谢
Thanks.
别误会了　我并不反对同鳏夫结婚（男主角丧偶）
Don't get me wrong. I'm not against marriage perse,
不过那必须得是个非常特别的人才能让我
but it'd take a pretty special guy to make me
愿意再次走在教堂的红地毯上
want to walk down that aisle again.
没错，这件事比不得其他，你不该轻率决定
Yeah, it's not something you should enter into lightly.
总的来说就是需要尊重
It boils down to respect.
如今人们已经不再尊重婚姻
People just don't respect the institution of marriage anymore.
他们对什么叫做一辈子的承诺毫无概念
They have no sense of real commitment.
嗯，我很想坐在这里跟你好好聊聊
Well, I'd love to stay here and chat,
不过我很快就要看完了，我很想知道是怎样的结局
but I'm right at the end, and I gotta find out what happens.
你...
You...
你这卑鄙的家伙　你怎么可以这样做?
You dirty bird. How could you?
她不能死！米瑟瑞 查斯顿不能死！
She can't be dead! Misery Chastain cannot be dead!
安妮，在1871年，妇女通常在生产时死亡
Annie, in 1871, women often died in childbirth.
但她的精神才是最重要的
But her spirit is the important thing,
米瑟瑞的精神仍旧活着
and Misery's spirit is still alive.
我不要她的精神！我要她活着！
I don't want her spirit! I want her!
而你却杀了她！
And you murdered her!
不　我没有
No. I didn't.
那是谁呢?
Who did?
没有谁　她死了，她就这样不经意间远离了
No one. She died, she just slipped away.
不经意间远离了？不经意间远离了？
Slipped away? Slipped away?
她不会就这样离开的！是你杀了她！
She didn't just slip away! You did it!
是你！是你！
You did it! You did it!
是你杀了她！是你杀了她！你杀了我的米瑟瑞！
You did it! You did it! You murdered my Misery!
安妮!
Annie!
我原本以为你是个好人，保罗
I thought you were good, Paul.
但你不是　你只不过是另一个撒谎的卑鄙的老家伙
But you're not good. You're just another lying old dirty birdie.
我想我还是离开你一会儿比较好
And I don't think I better be around you for a while.
别指望会有任何人来找你
And don't even think about anybody coming for you.
医生，你的经纪人，还有你的家人，谁都不会来
Not the doctors, not your agent, not your family,
因为我根本就没有通知他们
because I never called them.
没人知道你在这儿
Nobody knows you're here.
你最好希望我别出什么事
And you better hope nothing happens to me.
因为我要是死了，你一个人也活不成
Because if I die, you die.
不，辛德尔女士，你就算现在赶来也没有意义
No, Miss Sindell, there's no point in comin' up here now.
我们已经尽力了
Everything that can be done is.
是的，我们同州警察密切协作
Yes, we're working close with the state police
并且也将此事通知了联邦调查局
and the FBI's been informed.
好的　好的　一旦我们有什么消息就会立刻通知你的
Right. Right. As soon as we know anything, we'll let you know.
一点也不麻烦　随时都可以来电话　再见，辛德尔女士
No bother at all. Call anytime. Bye, Miss Sindell.
好的　那么，非常感激你所做的一切　谢谢
All right. Well, I sure appreciate it. Thank you.
根据对谢尔顿的信用卡支付记录调查显示
According to the check on Sheldon's credit charges,
在银溪郡之后，没有别的地方的使用记录
there's nothing after the Silver Creek.
同样，也没有接到关于手稿的电话
And no calls about the article, either.
你这可怜的，讨人喜欢的家伙　你躺在地板上干什么呢？
You poor, dear thing. What are you doing on the floor?
都是我的错
It's all my fault.
要是我有一张正规的医院病床这样的事永远也不会发生
If I'd had a proper hospital bed this never would've happened.
来吧，让我把你扶到床上去
Here, let me help you back in.
我知道这会有点疼，不过只要忍几秒钟就好了
I know this hurts, but it'll only take a few seconds.
起！
Upsy-daisy!
拜托，慢点儿
Please, wait.
你这个宝宝还真是爱哭
You're such a crybaby.
行了　还舒服吧？
There you go. Comfy?
非常好
Perfect.
你真是孩子气
You're such a kidder.
我有一个大大的惊喜要给你
I have a big surprise for you.
但首先你必须做件事情
But first there's something you must do.
你不会介意在我等待这个惊喜的时候
You don't suppose I could have a little snack
给我来点儿点心吧？
while I'm waiting for the surprise?
你要什么我都会给你，不过你先得听我说完
I'll get you everything you want, but you must listen first.
有时候我的思维有点儿混乱，这我承认
Sometimes my thinking is a little muddy, I accept that.
这也是为什么我想不起
That's why I couldn't remember
他们在丹佛向我出示证据时所提的那些问题是什么的原因
all the things they were asking me on the witness stand in Denver.
不过这次我的想得很清楚
But this time I thought clearly.
我问上帝该怎样看待你在我这里一事
I asked God about you,
上帝回答说：“我把他交给你”
and God said, "I delivered him unto you"
”这样你就能够为他指引道路了“
"so that you may show him the way."
为我指引道路?
Show me the way?
没错
Yes.
我说的是点心
When I mentioned a snack,
我考虑得更多的是电话线
I was thinking more along the lines
乳酪还有干酪、饼干诸如此类的东西
of cheese and crackers kind of thing.
保罗，现在不是开玩笑的时候
Paul, this is no time for jokes.
你必须让这件污秽之物从这个世上消失
You must rid the world of this filth.
你要我烧掉自己的书？
You want me to burn my book?
我知道要你这样做很难，但这是最好的办法
I know this may be difficult for you, but it's for the best.
其实也没这么困难
It's really not difficult at all.
我的经纪人做了许多副本
My agent made dozens of copies.
在纽约还会有场手稿拍卖会
There's gonna be an auction in New York.
现在纽约的每家出版社都在看这本书
Every publishing house in New York is reading it now.
因此如果你希望我烧了我的书，那好吧
So if you want me to burn my book, fine.
你并没有让任何东西从这个世界上消失
You're not really ridding the world of anything.
那就划火柴把，保罗
Then light the match, Paul.
这没什么大不了的
It's no big deal.
既然你已经说没什么了　那就动手吧
So you've indicated. Do it.
我知道这是唯一的一本，保罗
I know this is the only copy, Paul.
在你24岁写出自己第一本书的时候，你就没有留下副本
When you were 24 you wrote your first book, and you didn't make a copy
因为你根本没想到会有人重视它
because you didn't think anybody would take it seriously.
但是他们很重视　于是自此以后你从来都不留副本
But they did. And ever since you've never made any copies
因为你迷信
because you're superstitious.
这也是为什么你总是回到那家银溪旅馆
It's why you always come back to the Silver Creek Lodge.
这是一年前你对梅尔夫 格里芬说的
You told that story to Merv Griffin1 years ago.
梅尔夫 格里芬（FUCK）
Merv Griffin.
我告诉你吧　这本书不会出版
I'll tell you what. It doesn't ever have to be published.
没人有机会可以看到
No one ever has to read it.
我只是为自己留着的
I'll just keep it for myself.
没人会知道它的存在
No one will even know it exists.
这本书一天不毁掉，你的思想就永远也得不到解放
As long as it does exist, your mind won't ever be free.
我觉得你应该把火柴点着，保罗
I think you should light the match, Paul.
你就看不出这是上帝的旨意吗？
Can't you see it's what God wants?
你这样的聪明
You're so brilliant,
我想你毫无疑问会明白的
I would think you'd certainly be able to see that.
我们到这个世上是来帮助别人的，保罗
We're put on this earth to help people, Paul.
正如现在我想帮助你一样
Like I'm trying to help you.
拜托　让我帮助你吧
Please. Help me help you.
你正在做的是一件正确的事情
You're doing the right thing.
我的天哪！仁慈的上帝啊！噢，我的天
My goodness! Goodness gracious! Oh, my.
无题 保罗 谢尔顿著
天呀！上帝啊！
Goodness! Heavens to Betsy!
噢，我的天哪！噢，我的天哪！
Oh, my goodness!　Oh, my goodness!
上帝啊！噢，我的天！
Heavens to Betsy! Oh, goodness!
好了，烧得还算彻底吧？
Well, isn't that an oogy mess?
下边是斯蒂曼家
That's the Steadman place down there.
往前面是威尔克斯农场
And that's the Wilkes farm straight ahead.
没有65年的野马车
That's no '65 Mustang.
这里没甚么了，我们... 我们回去吧
There's nothing else out this way. Let's... Let's circle back.
我相信冬季会
I do believe the winters are getting
一年比一年短
shorter and shorter every year.
人们说这跟臭氧层有关
People say it has something to do with the ozone layer.
你认为呢?
What do you think?
我不知道
I don't know.
是的，当然，这只是个理论
Yeah, well, it's a theory.
这是你今天的Novril
Here's your Novril.
好了　我们又回到了现场
All right. We're back.
现在，你们将告诉我们现场观众们选择了谁
Now, you're gonna have to remind us who the audience chose.
他们选了凯文　他们选了凯文
They chose Kevin. They chose Kevin.
- 嗨，凯文　　- 嗨，你好吗，查克?
- Hi, Kevin　　- Hi. How you doin', Chuck?
好的　就当在自己家一样，别紧张
Fine. Make yourself at home back there
接下来谢瑞会告诉我们关于本次约会的事
and Sheree will tell us about the date.
OK　首先，我挑选了一家非常漂亮的餐厅
Okay. First of all, I picked out a very classy restaurant.
那里太漂亮了，而他竟然没有打领带就出现了…
It was so classy, and he shows up without no tie...
看见没，是不是很好看?
See, isn't this nice?
非常好　我一直想到房间的另一头去转转
Great. I always wanted to visit the other side of the room.
看看我都给你买了什么
And look what I got for you.
一支电动刮胡刀，这样今后你就能自己刮胡子了
An electric razor, so you can shave yourself now.
如果我早知道惊喜就是指的这个，我宁愿烧掉我所有的书（崩溃）
If I knew this was gonna be the surprise, I'd have burned all my books.
别耍嘴皮子了！
Now, don't poke fun!
今天对你来说可是相当重要的日子，保罗
This is a very big day for you, Paul.
你只要好好的坐着就行，我会把一切都安排好的
You just sit tight and I'll set everything up.
安排什么?
Set what up?
那是个大惊喜
That's the big surprise.
你的新工作室
Your new studio.
毕竟，作家需要有地方来工作
After all, writers do need a place to work.
工作？你是指写作？
Work? You mean write?
你凭什么认为我得写作呢？
What in the world do you think I'd write?
保罗，我不认为我知道
Paul, I don't think. I know.
现在你已经毁掉了那份龌龊的手稿
Now that you've gotten rid of that nasty manuscript,
你可以重新开始做你擅长的事
you can go back to doing what you're great at.
你即将写出一本新的小说
You're gonna write a new novel,
那将是你最为杰出的作品
your greatest achievement ever.
米瑟瑞归来
Misery's Return.
米瑟瑞归来?
Misery's Return?
我知道在你杀掉她的时候自己心里其实并不是这样想的
I know you didn't mean it when you killed her,
现在你可以纠正它
and now you'll make it right.
这将是一本为答谢我
It'll be a book in my honor,
救命之恩的感恩之作
for saving your life and nursing you back to health.
保罗，你将令我成为全世界羡慕的对象！
Paul, you're gonna make me the envy of the whole world!
你是希望让我匆忙间写点什么，对吧？
You just expect me to whip something off, is that it?
我期望是一部任何方面都不输给你以往杰作的作品
I expect nothing less than your masterpiece.
你应该知道书可不是这样写出来的
You do understand that this is not the ordinary way in which books get written.
我的意思是，人们会认为这真的是一个很古怪的写作环境
I mean, some people might actually consider this an oddball situation.
我对你的才华完全有信心
I have total confidence in your brilliance.
此外，这里的美丽风景也会激发你的灵感
Besides, the view will inspire you.
你就好好的大吃一顿吧　我很快就回来
You just inhale that. I'll be right back.
我猜你的邻居不是经常来麻烦你
I guess you don't get bothered by neighbors much.
那个你一点都不用担心
Don't you worry about that
你现在已经完全与世隔绝，这样你就能专注于写作上
you'll have total solitude so you can concentrate on your work.
非常好（无奈）
Great.
我给你买来了这种高价的打字纸
I got you this expensive paper to type on
而这个打字机买得很划算，只花了50镑
and I got a great deal on this 50-pound clunker
因为它的字母“N”给掉了
on account of its missing an "N."
我对女售货员说，“N”是我最喜欢的作家名字中的字母
I told the saleslady "N" was one of the letters in my favorite writer's name.
而我最喜欢的护士的名字中这个字母出现了两次，她叫安妮
It's two of the letters in my favorite nurse's name, A-nn-ie.
你这个傻瓜（被男主角之前作品影响了）！我干得不错吧？
You fooler! Did I do good?
你做得非常好
You did great.
不过只有一件小事
There is just one little thing.
我没法用这些纸写作　你看，全都黏在一起　这样字容易被弄花
I can't work on this paper. See, it's Corrasable Bond. It smudges.
因此我想可以的话，你能不能到镇上去一趟
So I thought maybe, if you went back into town
给我买些白色的长纹纸回来
you could bring me some white long-grain mimeo.
但我买的是最贵的，我就不明白它怎么会被弄花呢
But mine cost the most, so I don't see how it can smudge.
过来，我给你看看
Come here, I'll show you.
弄花了
真的容易弄花，但话说回来　这看上去不是挺好看的嘛
It does smudge, after all. Isn't that fascinating.
我原本以为你会喜欢的
I thought you'd be interested.
我想让你参与写作的一切，安妮
I'd like for you to be in on everything, Annie.
不只是写完这本书，还有看着它是怎样写成的
Not just the finished book, but how it's written.
谢谢你替我着想这么多
Thank you for thinking of me.
我到镇上的时候还需要买别的什么吗？
Anything else I can get while I'm in town?
还有别的什么重要要求需要满足的吗？
Any other crucial requirements that need satisfying?
你需要一个袖珍录音机吗？
Would you like a tiny tape recorder?
或者买双手工制作的适合写作时穿的拖鞋？
Or how about a handmade set of writing slippers?
不，把纸买来就可以了
No, just the paper will be fine.
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
因为如果你希望的话，我可以把整座商店都给你搬回来
'Cause if you want, I'll bring back the whole store for you.
安妮，怎么了？
Annie, what's the matter?
怎么了？让我告诉你怎么了！
What's the matter? I'll tell you what's the matter!
我所做的一切都是为了你！
I go out of my way for you!
我想方设法的让你高兴！
I do everything to try and make you happy!
我喂你吃饭，给你擦洗身体，替你穿衣服，可你是怎样报答我的？
I feed you, I clean you, I dress you, and what thanks do I get?
”你买错纸了，安妮“
"You bought the wrong paper, Annie.
”我没法在这种纸上写作，安妮！“
"I can't write on this paper, Annie!"
好的，我会把你要的蠢蛋纸买来
Well, I'll get your stupid paper
但是你最好表现出对我
but you just better start showing me
更多一点儿的感激之情，先生！
a little more appreciation around here, Mister Man!
该死
Shit.
来吧，你在书里边写过这个的，现在就试试吧
Come on, you've written about this, now do it.
你有想过吗？这还真的管用
What do you know? It actually works.
真令人惊奇
What a surprise.
你这个疯婆娘
You crazy bitch.
保罗，我把你要的纸买回来了
Paul, I've got your paper.
我希望这些应该够了　这是60刀长纹纸（刀，张数单位，一刀24张）
I hope it's enough. It's three reams of long-grain mimeo.
正是你要的那一种
Just the kind you asked for.
保罗，你在流汗
Paul, you're dripping with perspiration.
你脸色看上去很红　你刚才在干嘛？
Your color is very hectic. What have you been doing?
该死的你应该很清楚我刚才在干嘛
You know damn well what I've been doing.
我一直坐在这里忍受着痛苦
I've been sitting here suffering
我要吃药
I need my pills.
亲爱的你真可怜　等我把你扶上床再去替你把药拿来
Poor dear. Let's get you back in bed and I'll get them for you.
我现在就要！
I want my pills now!
一会儿就好
It'll only take a second.
不！
No!
我要马上止痛，安妮
I want my pain to go away, Annie.
求你了，给我止痛
Please, make it go away.
求求你，安妮　求你了
Please, Annie. Please.
看见你这个样子真叫我心碎
It just breaks my heart to see you like this.
我在开车的时候想了很多
I've done a lot of thinking on the drive.
给你
Here you go.
我很肯定自己从不招人喜欢的主要原因
And I'm absolutely certain the main reason I've never been more popular
就是因为自己的脾气
is because of my temper.
你现在一定很生我的气　跟我说实话吧
You must be so mad at me. The truth, now.
嗯…有谁不会偶尔发泄点儿脾气呢？
Well... Who doesn't let off a little steam every once in a while?
我的天才在写作前需要休息
My genius needs his rest before he writes.
双脚抬起来
Footsies up.
行了
There you go.
给你这个　你有什么灵感的时候可以记下来免得忘了
Here. In case you think of any ideas.
噢，我可不希望经常用到它
Well, I wouldn't expect too much.
别说傻话了！你会有灵感的
Don't be silly! You'll be brilliant.
可以把我当作你的灵感之源
Think of me as your inspiration.
我对你有信心，亲爱的（好想翻成：我看好你哦）
I have faith in you, my darling.
接着
Catch this.
“亲爱的”
"My darling."
据推断保罗 谢尔顿现在极有可能已经死亡
The presumption must now be that Paul Sheldon is dead.
我们知道他设法爬出了车外
We know that he somehow managed to crawl outside his vehicle,
不过我们没能在事故现场附近地区找寻到他的尸体
but we have been unable to find his body anywhere in the vicinity of the accident.
我们还知道要是有人发现他的话
We also know that if anyone had found him
他们会将他送到地区医院去的
they would have taken him to an area hospital.
毫无疑问他被埋在附近这些积雪中的某个地方
Undoubtedly he is buried somewhere out there in the snow.
等雪融化后我们便能找到他
We'll find him after the first thaw.
当然，这首先要他没被野兽吃掉才行
That is, unless the animals didn't get to him first,
但这是极有可能发生的
which is a distinct possibility.
地方报纸...
Local papers...
刚才是由科罗拉多州警察总长谢尔曼 道格拉斯发表的
That was a statement from Colorado Police Chief Sherman Douglas.
关于著名小说家保罗 谢尔顿失踪事件的说明
The where abouts of famed novelist Paul Sheldon is...
我们会继续为您报道有关该事件的最新消息…
We will be updating you with the latest...
你并不认为他已经死了，对吗？
You don't think he's dead, do you?
嗯，他也许是死了，但不是他们说的那样
Well, he might well be, but not the way they say.
他根本没可能自己爬出那辆车
He never crawled out of that car by himself.
你可以看见车门上有凹痕
You can see the dents on the door there.
有人把他弄了出来
Someone pulled him out.
该死的…
很抱歉，保罗　但这完全不对
I'm sorry, Paul. This is all wrong.
什么？
What?
你得全部重写
You'll have to do it over again.
它不值得你继续写下去　把它扔掉吧
It's not worthy of you. Throw it all out.
除了那个以我的名字命名的挖墓者
Except for that part of naming the gravedigger after me.
你可以继续保留它
You can leave that in.
我真的很重视你的评论
I really value your criticism
或许是我们都有点仓促了
but maybe we're being a little hasty here.
保罗，你写的不合理
Paul, what you've written just isn't fair.
不合理?
Not fair?
没错
That's right.
我小时候在贝克尔斯菲（城市，位于美国加州）
When I was growing up in Bakersfield,
那时这个世界上我最喜欢的就是
my favorite thing in all the world
周六下午到电影院看连续剧
was to go to the movies on Saturday afternoons for the chapter plays.
绝岭雄风（影片名）
Cliffhangers.
那个我知道，先生！
I know that, Mister Man!
他们还叫它系列剧　我可不是傻瓜，这你该知道！
They also call them serials. I'm not stupid, you know!
不管怎样，我最喜欢的还是火箭人
Anyway, my favorite was Rocketman,
有一次播出没有刹车那集
and once it was a no-brakes chapter
怀人们坏人把他困在山路上的一辆汽车里
and the bad guys stuck him in a car on a mountain road,
把他打晕了然后把门关上焊死
and knocked him out and welded the doors shut
之后他们破坏了刹车然后把车推了出去
and tore out the brakes and started him to his death.
当他醒来后就试着控制方向然后逃出去
And he woke up and tried to steer and tried to get out,
但是在他逃出之前汽车掉下了悬崖
but the car went off a cliff before he could escape,
汽车摔在地面起火燃烧
and it crashed and burned
而我是如此不安但又说不出的兴奋！
and I was so upset and excited!
而第二个星期，你最好相信我那时坐在第一排
And the next week, you better believe I was first in line.
他们开始放映前通常都会重播上周的结尾
And they always start with the end of the last week
放的还是火箭人正在试图逃出那段（这个故事有寓意）
and there was Rocketman, trying to get out
眼看就快到了悬崖那里
and here comes the cliff
就在汽车冲出悬崖的一瞬间他跳了出来
and just before the car went off the cliff he jumped free
于是所有的孩子们都欢呼起来！
and all the kids cheered!
但是我没有欢呼　我立刻站起来大声喊道
But I didn't cheer. I stood right up and started shouting
“上周演的不是这样的！（女主角那时就有反脱出心理）
"This isn't what happened last week!
你们全都得了健忘症吗？“
Have you all got amnesia?
”他们在愚弄我们！这不合理！“
"They just cheated us! This isn't fair!"
”他没能从那辆欠日的车里逃出来！“
"He didn't get out of the cockadoodie car!"
他们在连续剧里经常这样愚弄人
They always cheated like that in chapter plays.
但你不能这样　不能这样对我的米瑟瑞但
But not you. Not with my Misery.
还记得伊安骑马去找柯利尔医生吗？
Remember Ian did ride for Dr. Cleary
就在上一本书的结尾，但是他的马没能跃过那道篱笆
at the end of the last book, but his horse fell jumping that fence,
于是伊安摔伤了肩膀和肋骨，一整夜都躺在那条沟里
and Ian broke his shoulder and his ribs and lay all night in the ditch
他根本不可能到达医生那儿
and he never reached the doctor
因此也就没可能进行什么试验性的输血
so there couldn't have been any experimental blood transfusion
来拯救她的生命
that saved her life.
于是最终米瑟瑞长眠于地下，保罗
Misery was buried in the ground at the end, Paul
所以你要从那时候开始写
so you'll have to start there.
这样就合理了？那我还继续写吗？
Is it fair? Should I continue?
你最好这样！
You better!
噢，保罗！当伊安意识到
Oh, Paul! When Ian realized that
他们之所以会将米瑟瑞活埋是因为
the reason they'd buried Misery alive
蜂蜇让她暂时陷入了昏迷！
was because the bee sting had put her in that temporary coma!
而当挖墓工威尔克斯回想起30年前
And when Gravedigger Wilkes remembered how 30 years earlier
同样的事也在伊芙莲 海德小姐身上发生过！
the same thing had happened to Lady Evelyn-Hyde!
于是年迈的柯利尔医生就此推断米瑟瑞
And then old Dr. Cleary deduced that Misery
必定是伊芙莲 海德小姐失散多年的女儿
must be Lady Evelyn-Hyde's long-lost daughter
这罕见的致命蜂蜇教我的心都要跳出来了！
because of the rarity of deadly bee stings, my heart just leapt!
从第一本书开始我就知道
I've known from the very first book
米瑟瑞必定出身贵族
that Misery had to be born of nobility
看来我没有猜错！
and I was right!
没错（接着无语）
Yeah.
保罗，等你完成每个章节后就能立刻让我看吗？
Paul, can I read each chapter when you're finished?
我可以补上那些”N“
I can fill in the "N's."
现在伊安将她从墓里挖出来，她是会跟从前一样
Will she be her old self now that Ian has dug her out
还是会失去记忆?
or will she have amnesia?
那你的等着
Have to wait.
她依然会以那种特别的，完美的方式去爱着他吗？
Will she still love him with that special, perfect love?
你还是得等
You'll have to wait.
一点儿提示都没有？
Not even a hint?
嗯-哼
Uh-uh.
米瑟瑞没有死，米瑟瑞还活着！这太浪漫了！
Misery's alive, Misery's alive! It's so romantic!
这让整间屋子都充满了浪漫的气息！
This whole house is gonna be filled with romance!
我要放利勃瑞斯的唱片！
I'm gonna put on my Liberace records!
你相当喜欢利勃瑞斯的，对吧？
You do like Liberace, don't you?
当他演出城市电波的时候
Whenever he played Radio City
你认为坐在第一排的人会是谁？
who do you think was right there in the front row?
我会一整天的放唱片，激发你的创作灵感
I'm gonna play my records all day long, to inspire you.
他一直都是我的最爱
He's my all-time favorite.
安妮
Annie.
今晚你能同我共进晚餐吗？
Would you have dinner with me tonight?
为了庆祝米瑟瑞的归来
To celebrate Misery's Return.
没有你的帮助我是办不到的
I couldn't have done it without you.
保罗
Paul.
这真是一种荣幸
It would be an honor.
不，他不在这里
No, he's not here.
我不知道他在什么地方
I don't know where he is.
他从来都不跟我做任何解释
He never tells me anything anymore.
很可能他在外面什么地方有了外遇吧
He's probably out havin' an affair somewhere.
等等　他回来了
Wait a minute. He's comin' in now.
是金 泰勒
It's Jim Taylor.
他想知道你跟谁有外遇
He wants to know who you're havin' an affair with.
金，你好吗？有什么事吗？
Hello, Jim. What's doin'?
金，这我们以前在电话中就说过了
Jim, we've been through this before.
只要你把长椅伸出你的店门
If you're gonna have benches out in front of your store
人们就会坐在上面
people are gonna want to sit on 'em.
当然，我也不喜欢他
Well, I don't like him, either,
但我不会走过去
but I'm not gonna come over there
叫他离开
and tell him to move.
替我问候丹尼斯　再见
Give my best to Denise. Bye.
嗯，不论她是谁，她一定很爱看书
Well, whoever she is, she sure likes to read a lot.
维吉尼亚，你觉得我仍旧”精力“充沛真是令我受宠若惊
Virginia, I'm flattered that you think I've got that much energy.
我认为即便我找不到保罗 谢尔顿
I figured that if I can't find Paul Sheldon,
但起码我能查出他到底在写什么
at least I can find out what he wrote about.
你想查出什么？
What do you expect to find?
一个人在暴风雪中开车驶下悬崖的故事？
A story about a guy who drove his car off a cliff in a snowstorm?
你看，又在对我进行嘲讽
You see, it's just that kind of sarcasm
不过这也让我们的婚姻相当刺激
that's given our marriage real spice.
[I'LL BE SEEING YOU PLAYING]
[SINGING] I'll be seeing you
In all the old familiar places
我希望你会喜欢
I hope you like it.
看上去棒极了
It looks wonderful.
你也一样
So do you.
我从没吃过这么好吃的肉糕　你是怎么做的？
I've never had meatloaf this good. What do you do to it?
我的秘诀就是从来都用新鲜的西红柿，而不是罐头里的
My secret is I only use fresh tomatoes, never canned.
此外为了增加一些口感
And to give it that little extra zip,
我将斯帕姆午餐肉同碎牛肉混合在一起
I mix in some Spam with the ground beef.
在纽约的餐厅里可吃不到这些
Can't get this in a restaurant in New York.
我们干一杯吧
Let's have a toast.
干杯?
A toast?
对　为米瑟瑞干杯
Yes. To Misery.
我来给你斟酒
Let me pour you some wine
不
No
为米瑟瑞干杯
To Misery.
等一下　我们得好好享受这顿晚餐　有蜡烛吗？
Wait. Let's do this right. Do you have any candles?
我不知道　但我想应该有
I don't know. I think so.
我这就去找找
I'll go look.
你是之前学过装饰还是说本身就有这个天赋呢？
Did you study decorating or do you just have a flair?
噢，你真坏！
Oh, you!
我不过是这些年来一直打理着这里罢了
I just picked things up over the years.
嗯，它的风格很像你
Well, it certainly says you.
你真这么认为吗?
You really think so?
绝对是那样
Absolutely.
听着，如果你找不到的话，也没关系
Listen, if you can't find any, it's okay.
我想现在这样也已经很不错了
I just thought it'd be nice.
你不是在开玩笑吧？要是有人之前跟我说自己有一天
Are you kidding? If anyone had ever told me that one day
会在自己的家里同保罗 谢尔顿一起共进烛光晚餐
I'd be having a candlelit dinner with Paul Sheldon in my own house
那我一定得好好检查自己的两条腿
I would have checked both legs
看看别人是拿哪条在开玩笑！
to see which one was bein' pulled!
这样可以吧?
Will this do?
太完美了
It's perfect.
为米瑟瑞还有安妮 威尔克斯干杯，是她令米瑟瑞复活了
To Misery and to Annie Wilkes, who brought her back to life.
保罗，每当一想到这个我就浑身起鸡皮疙瘩！
Paul, I get goose bumps every time I think about it!
天啊，我都做了什么?
My God, what have I done?
我很抱歉，保罗!
I'm so sorry, Paul!
我把你浪漫的干杯给搞砸了
I ruined your beautiful toast!
你会原谅我吗?
Will you ever forgive me?
来，我再倒一杯
Here, let me pour another one.
我们可以装作没有发生过这件事吗？
Can we pretend this never happened?
为米瑟瑞干杯
To Misery.
为米瑟瑞
第5章
第12章
保罗，毫无疑问这是你笔下最完美的米瑟瑞
Paul, this is positively the best Misery you've ever written.
第19章
这是你的药
Here's your pills.
安妮?
Annie?
安妮，怎么了？
Annie, what is it?
雨
The rain.
有时候下雨会令我心情阴郁
Sometimes it gives me the blues.
当你最初来到这里的时候
When you first came here
我只爱保罗 谢尔顿你作为作家的那部分
I only loved the writer part of Paul Sheldon.
但现在我意识到自己同样也爱着他其余的部分（有肉体的啊！崩溃）
But now I know I love the rest of him, too.
我很清楚你并不爱我
I know you don't love me.
别说你爱我
Don't say you do.
你是那样的英俊，才华横溢，还是世人皆知的名人
You're a beautiful, brilliant, famous man of the world
而我没有电影明星那样的模样和身材（但大妈你是电影明星）
and I'm not a movie-star type.
你永远也不会了解失去一个像你这样的人对我来说是多么恐怖的事
You'll never know the fear of losing someone like you
如果你跟我一样
if you're someone like me.
你为什么还要放弃我？
Why would you lose me?
书已经快完成了
The book's almost finished.
你的腿也好多了
Your legs are getting better.
很快你便会想要离开
Soon you'll be wanting to leave.
我干嘛要离开？我喜欢这儿
Why would I leave? I like it here.
你能这样说真好，不过我打赌这绝对不是真的
That's very kind of you, but I'll bet it's not altogether true.
我拿着这把枪
I have this gun.
有时我都在想着怎么使用它
Sometimes I think about using it.
我最好还是出去吧
I better go now.
说不定我会把子弹放进去
I might put bullets in it.
"有种凌驾于人类法律之上的审判"
"There is a justice higher than that of man.
"我会由他来裁决"
"I will be judged by Him."
什么?
What?
他们把米瑟瑞推上了法庭
They're haulin' Misery into court.
很不错
That's nice.
有种凌驾于人类法律之上的审判
There is a justice higher than that of man.
我会由他来裁决
I will be judged by Him.
保罗 谢尔顿到底身在何处?
据推测保罗 谢尔顿已经死亡
-失踪作家的汽车被发现埋在雪堆中
一路往事
本地投资银行家身亡
卡尔 威尔克斯坠楼身亡
（于父亲节怀念亲爱的爸爸）
（注意…这篇文章每个段落都是完全相同的）
护士学校最优秀的学生滚下楼梯摔死
同学们对发生这样不可思议的悲剧事件表示震惊
安妮 M 威尔克斯为护士学校赢得荣誉（书签：投给尼克松）
（注意照片下英文名为：安妮 C 威尔克斯）
（同样…文章每个段落完全相同，道具师太不专业养了）
1978年3月23日，星期一
本　地　新　闻　　　　（右上）讣告　　　　（右下）过气车王
安妮 威尔克斯进入　　　前高校教练在医院　　　　在住院期间
重症监护室担任护士　　经长时间医治无效死亡　　受到致命袭击
退休小儿科医生在昏迷状态　　威尔克斯被提名担任
下经本地医院医治无效死亡　　本郡首席妇产科护士
（道具师又在变本加厉的复制文章段落！）
1984年11月1日，星期四
婴儿露西在医院艰难挣扎5周后死去
其父母为孩子的离世心碎欲绝
Elridge郡纪念医院发生第二起新生婴儿死亡事件
（方框内：Elridge郡纪念医院这起婴儿死亡原因尚未查明）
医院护士因婴儿在院中死亡而受到质询
1984年12月7日，星期五
医院育儿室再次发生婴儿死亡
妇产科护士被判入狱
“魔鬼女士”因涉嫌造成近期发生的婴儿死亡事件而被捕
欢迎到来[情牵一线]
[MAN CHATTERING ON TV]
旧时的浪漫结合现代技术
你可听到约会对象的一切亲昵细节
早上见
See you in the morning.
本来现在应该进入这个节目的尾声了
I'm supposed to lead to the finale of my show right now,
但我度过了如此美好的时光...
but I'm having such a wonderful time that I have...
保罗
Paul.
嗯？
Hmm?
我知道你曾出去过
I know you've been out.
什么？
What?
你曾离开过你的房间
You've been out of your room.
不，我没有
No, I haven't.
保罗，我书房里的小陶企鹅一直都是面向着正南方向的
Paul, my little ceramic penguin in the study always faces due south
我不明白你在说些什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
陶企鹅?
Ceramic penguin?
你是在找这个吗？（大妈心细得很，企鹅都不放过，何况这个）
Is this what you're looking for?
我知道你曾出去过两次，保罗
I know you've been out twice, Paul.
起初我弄不明白你是怎么办到的
At first I couldn't figure out how you did it,
不过昨晚我找到了你的钥匙
but last night I found your key.
我知道自己把剪贴簿留在了外边
I know I left my scrapbook out.
我能想象你会怎么看我
I can imagine what you might be thinking of me.
不过要知道，保罗，这没什么
But you see, Paul, it's all okay.
昨晚我的思维相当清晰
Last night it came so clear.
我意识到你不过是需要更多时间
I realize you just need more time.
最终你会愿意留在这里
Eventually you'll come to accept the idea of being here.
保罗，你听说过
Paul, do you know about the early days
金伯利（南非）钻石矿场过去的事吗？
at the Kimberley diamond mines?
你知道他们是怎样对付那些偷钻石的土著工人的？
Do you know what they did to the native workers who stole diamonds?
别担心　他们没有杀掉他们
Don't worry. They didn't kill them.
那样就像仅仅因为坏了一根弹簧
That would be like junking a Mercedes
便丢弃一辆梅赛德斯奔驰车一样
just because it had a broken spring.
不，一旦他们抓住偷钻石的工人，他们就得设法保证
No, if they caught them they had to make sure
工人们既能够继续工作
they could go on working,
但同时再也不能逃走
but they also had to make sure they could never run away.
这个办法就被称为”跛行“
The operation was called "hobbling."
安妮，不管你现在打算做什么
Annie, whatever you're thinking about doing,
求你不要那样做
please don't do it.
安妮，看在上帝的…
Annie, for God's...
亲爱的　相信我
Darling. Trust me.
上帝的份上！
God's sake!
这是最好的办法
It's for the best.
安妮，求求你!
Annie, please!
快完了　还剩一只脚
Almost done. Just one more.
上帝，我爱你
God, I love you.
你这欠日的！
You cockadoodie!
去你的吧！
Turn on this!
你这个傻瓜！
You poop!
离它远点儿，好吗？
Just leave it, all right?
我喜欢那种口气！
I like that tone!
你要我跟你说多少遍？
How many times do I have to tell you?
我这些东西摆放都是有规律的！那该死的玩意儿在哪儿？
I have a system here! Where the hell is that thing?
什么玩意儿?
What thing?
就是那玩意儿！（我都糊涂了…）
The thing!
找到了，就在它应该待的位置上
Here it is, right where it's supposed to be.
这是什么？
What is it?
我也不太清楚　也许什么都不是
I'm not sure. Maybe nothin'.
噢，我很高兴你找到它了
Well, I'm glad you found it.
你又在刺激我了
There's that spice again.
医院育儿室再次发生婴儿死亡
妇产科护士被判入狱
“魔鬼女士”因涉嫌造成近期发生的婴儿死亡被捕
魔鬼女士声称自己无罪
威尔克斯站在法院外的台阶上对记者说：
“有种凌驾于人类法律之上的审判，我会由他来裁决”
过来，米瑟　过来
Come on, Misie. Come on.
嗨，小可爱
Hi, pumpkin.
真是孩子气！走吧，米瑟瑞
Such a kidder! Come on, Misery.
嘿，皮特
Hey, Pete.
老兄
Buster.
回答我几件事情
Answer me a couple things.
如果我能的话
If I can.
你有保罗 谢尔顿的新书吗?
Do you have any new Paul Sheldon books?
噢，之前我们有一堆呢
Well, we had a batch.
3天内全卖光了
Sold 'em all out in three days.
你说不定知道威尔克斯女士有没有从这里买过一本，你还记得吗？
You wouldn't happen to know if Miss Wilkes bought one of them, would you?
你不是在开玩笑吧？那位兄台只要每次一有新书出版
Are you kiddin'? Every time that fella writes a new book
她必定会要我替她把第一本留下
she has me set aside the first copy.
她最近有购买什么奇怪的东西吗？
Has she been buyin' anything odd lately?
安妮 威尔克斯女士？还不是老样子
Miss Wilkes? Same old stuff.
除非你觉得买纸也算奇怪
Lest you call paper odd.
报纸？
Newspaper?
不　是打字纸
No. The typin' kind.
就是那种　除此之外没什么好奇怪的
That kind. Nothin' odd about that.
威尔克斯女士做了什么不好的事吗？
Miss Wilkes done somethin'?
没事了
Not a thing.
我不认为自己会理解你　我给你做饭
I don't think I'll ever understand you. I cook your meals,
我全天24小时对你进行特护
I tend to you practically 24 hours a day
而你却不停地反抗我
and you continue to fight me.
我们俩什么时候才能建立某种信任呢？
（她的话越恶心越好，其实我也很辛苦）
When are we going to develop a sense of trust?
噢，我的天
Oh, my.
抱歉，我并非想要惊吓到你
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to startle you
但是你甚至都没有让我来的及敲门
but you didn't give me a chance to knock.
我猜你能从我的反应中看出
I guess you can tell from my reaction
我并不习惯于有人到访
I'm not all that used to visitors out here.
我能为你做什么吗？
What can I do for you?
嗯，我想知道，你是否碰巧知道什么关于保罗 谢尔顿的事吗？
Well, I was wonderin', do you happen to know anything about Paul Sheldon?
你想知道什么?
What do you want to know?
是这样，随便你告诉我什么都可能会有帮助
Well, anything you could tell me might help.
嗯，他45年前出生于马萨诸塞州的伍斯特郡
Well, he was born in Worcester, Massachusetts, 45 years ago
是富兰克林 谢尔顿和他妻子海伦 谢尔顿的独子
the only child of Franklin and Helene Sheldon,
学生时代成绩平平，主修历史…
mediocre student,majored in History...
嗯那些…那些并不是我想要知道的信息
Well that... That isn't exactly the kind of information I'm after.
你也知道，他已经失踪很长一段时间了…
You see, he's been missin' for quite some time now...
我知道　那让人很不安
I know. It's so upsetting.
我是他的头号书迷
I'm his number-one fan.
他的书我全都有　甚至他写下的每一句话
I've got all his books. Every sentence he ever put down.
我对自己拥有如此齐全的保罗 谢尔顿收藏感到非常骄傲
（这次先收活人，再收木乃伊噢～）
I'm so proud of my Paul Sheldon collection.
噢，我就是这样，话说起来没完没了
Well, here I am, prattling on
完全把礼貌二字抛到了九霄云外
and my manners have just flown away.
我还没邀请您进来坐一下呢　请
I haven't invited you in. Please.
谢谢
Thank you.
当然，你也一定知道那场可怕的事故了
Of course, you must know all about that horrible accident.
介意我四处看看吗?
Mind if I take a look around?
当然不会
Of course not.
那个事故几乎也要了我的命
That accident almost killed me, too.
当我从新闻中听到这个消息的时候我便开始祈祷
I prayed when I heard the news.
我跪下祈求那不是真的
I got down on my knees and I begged for it not to be true.
接下来我说的话也许会让您想发笑
You're gonna laugh at what I'm about to say
您就笑好了，我不在乎的
but go ahead, I don't care.
就在我祈祷的时候，上帝告诉我要我做好准备
When I was praying, God told me to get ready.
准备什么？
Get ready for what?
成为他的接替者
To be his replacement.
他给那么多人带来了如此多的欢乐
He gave so much pleasure to so many people
而这些天来世界正面临欢乐短缺
and there's a shortage of pleasure on the planet these days,
要是你没有注意到
in case you hadn't noticed.
上帝他告诉我，因为我是他的头号书迷
God told me, since I was his number-one fan,
因此我就该把自己当作保罗 谢尔顿继续编写新的故事
that I should make up new stories as if I was Paul Sheldon.
于是我便去了镇上买了部打字机
So I went to town, and I bought a typewriter,
还有打字纸
and paper to type on
同保罗 谢尔顿用的是一样的
the same kind Paul Sheldon used.
我把客房改成了一间写作室
And I turned the guest bedroom into a writing studio.
您想进去看看吗？
Would you like to see it?
当然
Sure.
就在这边
It's right this way.
我知道他是怎样写作的　他在之前的那些美妙的故事中
I know how he wrote. The kinds of words he used
都用了些什么样的词语
the wonderful stories he told.
我足足花了四周时间
I've spent the last four weeks
来试着模仿他的写作风格
trying to write like Paul Sheldon,
但是没有成功
but I can't do it right.
我不断的试着，我知道所有的词句，可写出来却又不一样了
I try and I try, and I know all the words, but it's just not the same.
噢，也许还要再花一些时间才能掌握
Well, maybe it takes a while to get the hang of it.
我可以让您看看已经写好的几百页
I could give you a couple of hundred pages of mine
然后您可以告诉我您认为它写得怎么样
and you could tell me what you think.
我对评论不在行
I'm not much of a critic.
嗯，我只是想…
Well, I just thought...
噢，瞧瞧我　你说不定会认为我这里从来就没来过客人！
Oh, look at me. You'd think I'd never had a guest before!
你想来杯热可可吗？
Would you like a nice hot cup of cocoa?
不，说真的，我不…
No, really, I don't...
这不麻烦
It's no trouble.
是己经弄好了的
There's some already made.
你一个人住在这里想必很孤单吧
Must get lonely, livin' out here all by yourself.
嗯，我总是说，若你不能独处
Well, I always say, if you can't enjoy your own company
又如何同别人相处呢
you're not fit company for anyone else.
嗯，你说得很有道理
Well, you've got a point there.
给你的
Here you are.
噢，谢谢，威尔克斯女士
Well, thanks, Miss Wilkes,
但我不想再耽误你的时间了
but I don't want to take up any more of your time.
我最好还是走了
I best be goin'.
不过你甚至都还没有尝一下你的那杯可可呢
But you didn't even taste your cocoa.
我肯定它的味道会相当好，不过我真的该回去了
I'm sure it's wonderful, but I really should be gettin' back.
如果您不介意，或许我
If you wouldn't mind, perhaps I could
找时间改日再来拜访你
pay you another visit sometime.
那我会很高兴的，现在您该认识路了
I'd be delighted, now that you know the way.
威尔克斯女士?
Miss Wilkes?
威尔克斯女士，你没事吧?
Miss Wilkes, are you all right?
我在这儿！
Here!
在这里！我在下面！
Here! I'm down here!
我在下面！
I'm down here!
谢尔顿先生？
Mr. Sheldon?
别难过了，保罗
Don't feel bad, Paul.
这是迟早都要发生的事
It was bound to happen sooner or later.
这是个预兆
It's a sign.
你看，我已经知道自己为什么被选中来救你的命了
You see, I've known for some time why I was chosen to save you.
我们俩注定就是要永远在一起的
You and I were meant to be together forever.
不过现在我们俩留在在这个世界的时间必须得结束了
But now our time in this world must end.
但是不用担心，保罗
But don't worry, Paul.
我已经做好了必要的准备
I've prepared for what must be done.
我在枪里放了两颗子弹，一颗是你的，一颗是我的
I put two bullets in my gun, one for you and one for me.
亲爱的，这将是多么美妙啊
Darling, it'll be so beautiful.
巫师牌®
木炭助燃剂
你品尝的是食物…而不是燃料！
不用害怕
Now don't be afraid.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
你说的对　我们注定就是要在一起的（恶心死自己）
And you're right. We are meant to be together.
我也知道我们必须得死
And I know we must die.
但是必须得让米瑟瑞活着
But it must be so that Misery can live.
我们能让米瑟瑞永远的活下去
We have the power to give Misery eternal life.
我们必须完成这本书
We must finish the book.
但是没时间了　很快其他人就会赶来的
But the time is now. Soon others will come.
它就快完成了
It's almost finished.
等到黎明时
By dawn
我们就能让米瑟瑞重新回到这个世界
we'll be able to give Misery back to the world.
我去给你弄些吃的
I'll fix you something to eat.
（三天三夜）（米瑟瑞在哭）
保罗，我都快迷死了！
Paul, I'm dying!
她最终是同伊安还是同温德松在一起？
Does she wind up with Ian or Windthorne?
你马上就能知道
You'll know very soon.
我刚开始看最后一章
I've just started the last chapter.
你知道，当我完成的时候，我希望一切都是完美的
You know, when I finish, I'd like everything to be perfect.
我会需要三样东西
I'll need three things.
什么东西？
What things?
你是说你不知道吗？
You mean you don't know?
我开玩笑而已，傻瓜
I was foolin', silly.
你需要一支香烟，你曾经吸烟不过戒掉了
You need a cigarette, because you used to smoke but you quit,
除了当你写完一本书的时候，你才会抽上一支
except when you finish a book, and you have just one.
还有点烟用的火柴
And the match is to light it
你还要一杯香槟，Dom Perignon牌的
and you need one glass of champagne, Dom Perignon.
没错，Dom Perignon牌的
Dom Perignon it is.
安妮，安妮？
Annie, Annie?
什么事，保罗？
Yes, Paul?
我快写完了
I'm almost done.
噢，保罗，这简直太浪漫了！
Oh, Paul, this is so romantic!
伊安同温德松为了娶米瑟瑞而进行决斗
Ian and Windthorne dueling for the right to Misery's hand.
是伊安赢了吗？可别告诉我
Does Ian win? Don't tell me.
是温德松赢了，是这样吗？
It's Windthorne, right?
你一分钟内就会知道所有的答案
You'll know everything in a minute.
去把香槟拿来
Get the champagne.
我做得还好吗？
Did I do good?
你做得非常完美
You did perfect.
只有一件事例外
Except for one thing.
这次我们要两只杯子
This time we'll need two glasses.
噢，保罗
Oh, Paul.
想想吧，这么多年来
Remember how, for all those years
一直都没有人知道谁才是米瑟瑞的生父？
nobody knew who Misery's real father was?
或者他们能否重聚？
Or if they'd ever be reunited?
答案全部都在这里
It's all right here.
她最终是嫁给伊安，还是温德松？
Does she finally marry Ian, or will it be Windthorne?
也全都在这里
It's all right here.
保罗，你不能这样！
Paul, you can't!
为什么不能？我从你那里学的
Why not? I learned it from you.
不，不，不要！米瑟瑞！不要毁掉我的米瑟瑞！
No, no, no! Not Misery! Not my Misery!
不！不要毁掉我的米瑟瑞！
No! Not my Misery!
我要杀了你，你这个撒谎的贱人！
I'm gonna kill you, you lying cocksucker!
来呀，你想拿回它吗？你想要吗？吃下去吧！
Here, you want it? You want it? Eat it!
吃到噎死你，你这个恶心，变态的疯子！
Eat it till you choke, you sick, twisted fuck!
一年半之后
这就是第一本
（书名：J.飞利浦 史东的高等教育）
This is it. The very first copy.
我听说时代杂志对这本书的评论好像不错
The word I'm getting is the Times review is gonna be a love letter.
那还是第一次
That'll be a first.
我在时代周刊和新闻周刊的联络人告诉我他们都极力赞扬这部作品
And my contacts at Time and Newsweek tell me they're both raves.
不要笑，但这还是第一次
And don't laugh, but for the first time
我觉得你会获得什么奖项
I think you've got a shot at some prizes.
很好
Great.
我原本以为你会很激动
I thought you'd be thrilled.
你终于被认真看待了
You're being taken seriously.
我很高兴评论家们喜欢它
I'm delighted the critics are liking it
同样我希望读者们也喜欢
and I hope the people like it, too.
但那时我为自己写的
But I wrote it for me.
别当我疯了，不过…
Now, don't think I'm completely nuts, but...
以某种方式来说，安妮 威尔克斯
In some way, Annie Wilkes,
以及那整段经历
that whole experience,
确实给了我帮助
helped me.
保罗，既然你提起她
Paul, since you brought her up
我得问你一下否则我会被逐出经纪人联会
I have to ask you this or I'll be drummed out of the agents' union.
要是把在那间屋子里发生的事情写成一部纪实文学你觉得怎样？
How would you feel about a non-fiction book about what went on in that house?
噢，马修，如果我不是这么了解你，我会认为你提议
Gee, Marcia, if I didn't know you better, I'd think you were suggesting
要我发掘自己这一生中最为恐怖的经历出来
I dredge up the worst horror of my life
只是为了让我们能够赚几个钱
just so we can makea few bucks.
我还以为你已经摆脱那件事了
I thought you were over it.
我不知道是否有人可以完全忘掉那样的事情
I don't know if anyone could ever totally get over something like that.
这很奇怪
It's weird.
虽然我知道她死了
Even though I know she's dead,
不过我偶尔仍会想起她
I still think about her once in a while.
对不起　我并非想要打扰你们，但您就是保罗 谢尔顿吗?
Excuse me. I don't mean to bother you, but are you Paul Sheldon?
是的
Yes.
我只想告诉您我是您的头号书迷
I just want to tell you I'm your number-one fan.
你真好
That's very sweet of you.
[SINGING] I'll be seeing you
In all the old familiar places
That this heart of mine embraces
All day through
In that small cafe
The park across the way
The children's carousel
The chestnut trees
The wishin' well
I'll be seeing you
In every lovely summer's day
In every thing that's light and gay
I'll always think of you that way
I'll find you In the morning sun
And when the night is new
I'll be looking at the moon
But I'll be seeing you
I'll be seeing you
In every lovely summer's day
I'll be seeing you in every thing that's light and gay
I'll always think of you that way
I'll find you In the morning sun
And when the night is new
I'll be looking at the moon
But I'll be seeing you